Why is it so important that the stones
on a real track are jagged? In the past,
train tracks used to have gaps in
between them. The gaps let the steel
tracks expand and contract with
temperature. And wheels hitting those
gaps made that the tuck the tuck the
tuck sound. But those gaps also slowed
the trains down. So, today's tracks are
welded into one seamless rail. No more
clickety-clack. But now with expanding
hot rail has nowhere to go. And if left
alone, the internal pressure would build
until finally the rails would violently
buckle into the zigzag. And that is
where those jagged [music] rocks come
in. The tracks are attached to these
sleepers and then embedded in those
[music] rocks. And their jaggedness
makes them physically interlock, which
creates a huge amount of friction. So,
when the steel rails expand and [music]
push on the sleepers, the jagged rocks
lock together and hold everything firmly
in place. That keeps the rail straight
even under huge internal pressure. But
if the rocks were smooth and round, then
vibrations from passing trains would
make them slide around and the [music]
track could quickly buckle. Subscribe
for more.